Register of the Sergei Stepanovich Chazov Papers
Hoover Institution Archives
Sergei Stepanovich Chazov papers,
1944-1957
2000C100
Chazov, Sergei Stepanovich
5 microfilm reels. (0.75 linear feet)
Hoover Institution on War, Revolution, and Peace Stanford, California 94305-6010
Play scripts, and lists of Russian refugees evacuated from China.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection is open for research.
Acquisition Information
Acquired.
Location of Originals
Originals in: Museum of Russian Culture, San Francisco.
Biographical Note
Russian-American journalist and playwright.
Scope and Content Note
S. S. Chazov was a playwright and editor of the San Francisco newspaper Russkaia zhizn' in the mid-1950s. The papers contain primarily his plays, as well as rolls of Russian Russians evacuated from China, sent to him as newspaper editor by the World Council of Churches. These rolls are located in the Russian refugees file.
Detailed processing and preservation microfilming for these materials were made possible by a generous grant from the National Endowment for the Humanities and by matching funds from the Hoover Institution and Museum of Russian Culture. The grant also provides depositing a microfilm copy in the Hoover Institution Archives. The original materials remain in the Museum of Russian Culture, San Francisco as its property. A transfer table indicating corresponding box and reel numbers is available at the Hoover Institution Archives.
The Hoover Institution assumes all responsibility for notifying users that they must comply with the copyright law of the United States (Title 17 United States Code) and Hoover Rules for the Use and Reproduction of Archival Materials.
Indexing Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the repository's online public access catalog.
Subjects
Russian literature.; Russians--China.; Russians--United States.; Refugees.; Russia.; China.; United States.
Series Description
- Writings, 1944-1957 and undated. (Box 1-5)
  Plays, screenplays, and operettas, arranged chronologically by title
- Russian Refugees File, 1953-1956. (Box 5)
  Rolls of Russian refugees evacuated from China
Container List
- WRITINGS, 1944-1957 and undated. (Box 1)
  - "Nakazannyi Don Zhuan," n.d. (Folder 1: 1)
    Typescript
  - "Okhotniki," n.d. (Folder 1: 2)
  - "Ruka," n.d. (Folder 1: 3)
  - "Dva vystrela," 1944. (Folder 1: 4)
  - "Eliksir molodosti," 1944. (Folder 1: 5)
  - "Tania," 1944 February. (Folder 1: 6)
  - "Kusochek schast'ia," 1944 October. (Folder 1: 7)
  - "Prodannyi rebenok," 1944 November. (Folder 1: 8)
  - "Tragediia v dramie," 1944 December. (Folder 1: 9)
  - "3 druga i chetvertyi Atlant," 1944 December. (Folder 1: 10)
  - "Diadiushka iz tetiushei," 1945 January. (Folder 1: 11)
    Typescript and holograph notes and diagrams on stage decorations and make-up
  - "Molodye poryvy," 1945 January. (Folder 1: 12)
  - "Sopernitsy," 1945 January. (Box-folder 2: 1)
  - "Oshibka," 1945 February. (Folder 2: 2)
    Typescript and diagrams of stage decorations
  - "Bielaia ruka," 1945 April. (Folder 2: 3)
  - "K novoi zhizni," 1945 November. (Folder 2: 4)
  - "Kak oni razoshlis'," 1946. (Folder 2: 5)
  - "Soviest'," 1947 August. (Folder 2: 6)
  - "K novym beregam," 1949. (Folder 2: 7)
  - "Kogda govorili orudiia," 1949. (Folder 2: 8)
    Typescript. Includes English translation entitled "When the Cannons Spoke"
  - "Liubov' v universal'nom magazinie," 1949. (Folder 2: 9)
  - "Ave Maria," 1949 June. (Box-folder 3: 1)
    Typescript. Includes English translation
  - "W5," 1950 February. (Folder 3: 2)
  - "Dva painta krovi," 1950 March. (Folder 3: 3)
  - "Zhit' stalo luchshe... Zhit' stalo veseliei," 1950 April. (Folder 3: 4)
  - "Pod serdtsem Gimalaev," 1950 June. (Folder 3: 5)
  - "'Kim Suim': Koreiskaia Mata Khari," 1950 September. (Folder 3: 6)
  - "Domik za roshchei," 1950 December. (Folder 3: 7)
  - "Serenada," 1951 June. (Folder 3: 8)
  - "Operatsiia 'Ke-Em'," 1955 March. (Box-folder 4: 1)
  - "Ego putevodnaia zvezda," 1955 May. (Folder 4: 2)
  - "Oni za rabotoi," 1955 May. (Folder 4: 3)
  - "Po tu storonu shirmy," 1955 May. (Folder 4: 4)
  - "Printsessa Zaula," 1955 May. (Folder 4: 5)
  - "Kto ubiitsa," 1955 November. (Folder 4: 6)
  - "Pis'mo k Bozhen'ke," 1956 June. (Folder 4: 7)
  - "Gorstochka rodnoi zemli," 1956 July. (Folder 4: 8)
  - "Starye, novye, noveishie," 1956 July. (Folder 4: 9)
  - "Strashno!" 1956 July. (Folder 4: 10)
  - "Printsessa Meriam," 1956 August. (Folder 4: 11)
  - "Vse sluchaetsia," 1956 August. (Folder 5: 1)
  - "Istoriia s tremia kliuchami," 1956 September. (Folder 5: 2)
  - "Kak oni spasli mir," 1956 September. (Folder 5: 3)
  - "Na putiakh nashei zhizni," 1957. (Folder 5: 4)
  - "Avantiura -- akt miloserdiia," 1957 May. (Folder 5: 5)
- RUSSIAN REFUGEES FILE, 1953-1956. (Folder 5: 6-7)
  Lists of names of Russians evacuated from China and attached correspondence